What happens when Mr. Franz and
Marcello Ascani meet again in
America and take a trip together after
10 years?  We discover it in this video
between San Francisco and the
Californian nature.  We left off with the
last vlog when I was in San Francisco,
I had attended the YC Demodi and I had
chatted with Irene Mingozzi,
partner at Italian Funders Fund who
told me the secrets behind the world
of venture capital.  That evening at Demo
Day we ended with a dinner among
Italians.  We took Wayo's
self-driving car and
went home.  This morning starts with
a jog along the San
Francisco waterfront.  I tried to take
Franzia with me, so a light,
slow jog.  I enjoyed the day.  We
arrived at a small park to train.   I
did a mini workout.  I
pretended to work out in reality and then
we went to a cafe and had
breakfast.
One of my dreams is to open something like this in Italy
that isn't a café,
you walk in and find yourself drinking coffee.   It
's crazy.
What's wrong with you?   I got myself
a lace and something with
purple powder.  On the way home
I smashed my iPhone into 1000 pieces,
so now I realize I should have Apple
Care, so maybe I'll stop by an Apple
Store to get my screen replaced.  By
chance, I had already stopped by the
Apple Store to buy the AirPods,
since I had lost them.  And this morning we're
at Innovit, which is a
government program to help
Italian startups here in San Francisco.  I'm
here with Franz because I actually told him
, "Look, there's no point in starting a
startup in Italy without coming here to San
Francisco to see what's
happening, it'll blow your mind."
In fact, Franza's brain is exploding
.  Today there's an event featuring all
the Italian startups on the topic of cyber
security.  They're doing a lot of
mentor meetings and stuff.  I
came because there's
a Shark Tank this afternoon.  I'll be a judge on
Shark Tank all day.
Marcello.
And now that you're, let's say, halfway through this
trip, how are you feeling?
Overwhelmed.  Sorry, I can't
speak Italian anymore.
How many startups do you want to do from one to many?
Three to date.  These days have passed.  Then
we'll see.  The panel that just ended,
which I didn't see, was with Andrea
Ccano, the founder of Noomy Networks,
one of the coolest companies created by
Italians abroad.  And he's a
crazy story, he sold the company for a
billion, if I'm not mistaken, even though
Italy hasn't
talked about it that much, and that's why I
suggested we interview him.  He said
absolutely yes, let's see if we can
find a gap because right now there's the
cyber security conference, so
obviously he's super mega busy, we
should be able to do it.
And big conul
Founders.  And
Mario from Belzzebub, in whom I
invested, also came to this Shark Tank.  How did it go?  [laughter]
Come on, this time it went much much much
better than the elevator.
San Francisco, what's it like?
San Francisco is so beautiful that
I think we'll
move here in the next few days.
Starting a startup here in Italy is a whole
different story.
Yes, yes.  Huge market, much
easier to network.
Giro, you were the public speaker.
It was me.  It was a pleasure to
speak publicly about this
wonderful company.
You did good, I must say.  You're just
good.  [applause][music]
I spent the whole afternoon at
Innovit judging with other
judges who were
very interesting Italian and foreign investment funds.  The
startups we awarded were
all in the defense and cybersecurity sectors,
so it was very interesting.  A market
that I don't know and so I also
learned a lot of things, but it was
devastating because I was there from
2:00 in the afternoon to 7:00 in the evening.
So, you won 10 fake million, are you
happy?  Tonight I'm paying.
Perfect.  Franz was with me and together
we went to have dinner, a big
steak, or rather a small steak, at
Manalisa, an Italian-American restaurant, and
then an ice cream to end the
day.
But this is what the mechanic has that's
open at 9:30.  But does it seem normal to you?
Will there be any trouble?
This morning is a beautiful day,
more meetings await me.
That morning we met the
mayor of San Francisco out on the
street and by pure chance we both
headed to the same cafe.  Poesia
Caffè, the new location opened by
Giovanni, whom I interviewed a year and
a half ago, where he told me about his
life as a pastry chef in San Francisco.
Good morning.
What has changed since our video?  What
happened?  Back.  We are in a second
location.  We changed the kitchen,
we opened Downtown where it's
practically being reborn thanks to
[music] by the mayor.  It basically
revolutionized everything.  San Francisco has
really been reborn and so we're here,
we're living this new [music]
adventure and we opened out here
basically there's a square called
One Post Plaza and we want to make it
become a real little Italian square
where people come for a beer,
slices of pizza.  We had
a great time with him, and
Oliviero Pinotti also joined us, a guy who was
admitted to W Combinator, who left
Combinator and who convinced me to
invest in his startup.  Afterwards, we
headed to the Market
Street office of CuA,
Francesco's startup that he also
convinced me to invest in last year.
And here on Market Street we have arrived at the
new Cua offices in which I invested
last year.  How is my
investment doing?   Is it
paying off?   I
'm happy.
Well.  Anything else to say?  We've moved to
this new office on Market Street.
Dillon here is our new CTO.
Hi al [laughter]
Not tired of peer startup guys we had
lunch with the guys from
Prospinity.  I also made a video with them
, but since that video everything has
changed because, like many startups, they have
completely changed their
business model and their company,
they even changed their
name.  [music]
That evening we went to Marina for
pizza with Tano and d'aria who together
run a tech community in San
Francisco.  The next day we
went back to the Y Combinator area, we had
breakfast there, but only because
I had to shoot the video at Pck Design
which, as you remember, I met the
founder a few days before and he has
the gigantic, beautiful office,
right nearby.  Video shot, we
came home, I took a classic
evening jog around San Francisco along the
waterfront, very nice, and then straight to
dinner at a Nepalese restaurant in the
company of Riccardo Giraldi.
I made a video with him too.  When I go back to
San Francisco I meet all the
fantastic, wonderful people I've
met over the years and it was with
him, who worked a few years ago at
Zukat, that I had the
definitive autonomous driving experience.  In fact, we
tried Zux, which, if you see, is
nothing like a car; it doesn't even have a
steering wheel.
Why is it in F more here?
No, it works, it works.
[music]
Which is very beautiful.
Now all that's missing is the weekend.  Tomorrow
morning we'll leave San Francisco,
get in a car, and take a little
trip out of town.  Enough talk
about startups, enough talk about KPIs,
Funnels, MCPs, AI,
proactive agents, vibe coding, now let's go
see the horses and touch the grass,
shall we?
I really hope so.  Yes, I mean,
he really hopes so.  Exact.  If 10 years
ago I could pick up, go, and travel
with Franza without worrying about
work, because it was just me, now I'm
a small entrepreneur, I have many
people working with me from Italy,
suppliers, employees, professionals.
In fact, after a while it's a constant stream of
bank transfers, invoices to collect, invoices
to record, and so if I want to
take even a few days off
work, as I did with Franz,
this time I have to be much more
organized, especially when it comes to payments.
My perfect ally is Vivid, a
tool that if you are an entrepreneur or
freelancer you must have for
your business account.  It combines
all the good things about a smart account
with all the reliability of a
traditional account, without the hassle of
managing large amounts of money.  Not only
is the interface easy to understand, so
you can see exactly how much cash flows,
how much money comes in, how much money
goes out, and it's easy to make
or schedule transfers with a click, even
pay F24s. But you can also manage
company cards, create cards for
your employees, manage limits and
access for each, block them
when necessary, and all of this means you
also receive interest on the money you keep in the
account, which is not typical with
company accounts.  What's more, if you want to
invest money, you can invest it
directly on Vivid, choosing from
all the various asset classes.
In short, Vivid is the ultimate business account
, so if you are a
professional or entrepreneur, go to the
description or click on the QR code
Franch March on the road,
the American adventure begins.  This morning
France rented a car, a
fantastic Nishan Cashkai.  Things?  What is one
?  Something that doesn't exist in Italy.  It's
a big car.  We went for
breakfast in Sout Salido.  We
crossed the Golden Gate Bridge.
We ate a delicious
breakfast, passed through the
peaceful protests of the
very rich inhabitants of Sao against the president,
and now we are heading towards a small
town, which we will reach by crossing
the ranches of California.  they say to each other.
[music]
We continued through the
boundless nature of California, beautiful,
the lakes, the greenery.  We
also passed through some western towns with the
salun, with the rench then arrive at
our destination town which is
Petaluma, where we took a hotel,
a Mariot Bonoi which costs less than San
Francisco, but is much nicer and now we are
heading towards the center of
Petaluma where there are some protests
underway, always the same as before, always
participated mostly by elderly people who
are peacefully occupying the center
of Petaluma which is in subio I imagine I have
n't seen anything like this for years.  It's
a delightful little village.  I think it's very
hot.  How many degrees are there?  77 degrees Fahrenheit
.  To be clear, Petalume is
that place that has Butter and Egg
Days, April 18th and April 26th.  [music]
Here.
And the store you were looking for is right here in
front of you.  Records.  There's a whole
street full of vinyl shops and the like.   Little
rocket from Mcneers.
There is also the McEars Theatre.  So,
McNears Musical Theatre.
Madonna.  Now let's go to the theater.
We also played hand-me-downs
[music]
in the hotel and did our laundry
because unfortunately my package from Los
Angeles never arrived, so
my jeans were 12 days old,
so I washed them.  We
also took a dip in the very
nice outdoor pool.  We're having a
killer heat, beautiful weather, a bit
of gym work and then straight to the adventure.
This time to have dinner with some
meat.  We went to a place that was a
5-minute drive from the hotel, very
American, very traditional, perfect
for us, men full of testosterone.
We ate meat, there was a
band of old men playing beautiful
rock songs, there were little girls and
women dancing in circles, a
wonderful bonfire and now we are looking for a
dessert.  Since I've been here I haven't
had cheesecake yet, so we
're heading to a
cheesecake place.
We found this beautiful place,
lost in the middle of nowhere, that was
very cheap.  We had two slices of
cake and a hot chocolate, my
stomach was exploding and we spent
$15 which if we had done it in San
Francisco we would have spent in fact
I gave him a $5 tip because I am a
respectful tycoon.  And now a new
day and we are heading towards Sonoma,
another of these California towns,
where we go to have breakfast Francez.
I would like a pancake, or rather a blueberry
pancake to be specific.   Here they are
, while I have the proteins.
[music]
Back on the road.  What travelers, what
adventurers, what madmen, what crazy people who
travel through America.
Franz took me to the [music]
train amusement park, where the average age
was 5 and then there was me and Franz.
For $9 [music] each we took a
20-minute ride on the little train that went
around the entire amusement park
which was a sort of miniature Wild West town [music]
.  In fact, the train
also stopped at a
miniature Wild West set where we were able to
cuddle the alpaca and goats.  Very
nice.  Even though we were off target, it was
actually really fun and
really cute.  Then another 10 minutes by
car to get to the city center of
Sonoma, a very nice little square,
very touristy.  We went around
all the little places,
vintage shops, things like that.  We
then stopped for lunch, we
ate two huge sandwiches
each, really full of
cheese, chicken, avocados, we
ate a lot.  And we
spent like $80, a lot this time,
because the place was a bit
touristy.  In my opinion, most
of the people who were there both at the
[music] amusement park and in the city
were people from San Francisco, from the
city who came for a Sunday
outing.  Now, still more or less 10
minutes away, 20 minutes, we
arrived at Jack London Park, a
natural, historic park near
Sonoma, full of trees and nature.  We're going on
a little hike.  Look at this
bucolic place, it looks like Tuscany.  Jack
London is the famous writer who
wrote White Fang.  I didn't know he
lived in California, but this park
where we are right now is the estate
where he lived, you know, it was basically his home
.  I assume he was
awash in money because he had a
gigantic estate here in California and
above all that he knew how to enjoy life
because look how great he is, huh?
Our friend Jack London was in the chill,
writing, eating, and drinking like crazy
on his estate.  Bravo!  Jack London was
crazy about gas relief.  He worked here and
slept out here on the balcony separate
from his wife because he wrote until
late at night until morning.  1000
words every day by hand.  But oh my!
And here instead was where his wife
Sharmian was, also the writer who
in reality spent a lot of time
retyping Jack London's books
and reviewing them, therefore checking them.
So they actually wrote
those books as a team and that's exactly where he
died.  C Jack London is only 40 years old, he
wrote 50 books in 16 years and then
died at 40.  He traveled the world,
did a lot of things, very
early on.
[music]
Franz, but do you know how old Jack London
was when he wrote his first
novel?  14 27
and already from the first novel he became a
success, so he wasn't
rich before, before he hunted seals, he
even took part in the gold rush, he
wasn't a daddy's boy [music] and then
after having written the first book he
started writing like a madman every
day, all day and he wrote
all these novels
and he bought himself
Arberelli,
the good Jack woke up in the morning,
had a little coffee and he had this
vision.  Damn, oh!  Eh!
Darnit!
Oh, this view, eh!  Afterwards we
drove to our
hotel Sonoma In and Spa.
This little town, a bit mountainous, is very pretty, nestled along
a river in the middle of the mountains.  We
checked into the hotel,
checked in, and then I went for my
run because it's Sunday. I had to run
14 km, and I ran 12 because I had to
go back and forth up and down
the mountains. I went up all the way up
the mountain to get a view from above, then
down all the way down to the
river beach. It was beautiful, I
saw a lot of things, and now I'm really
tired.  [music] After a shower
, we head to a little
restaurant here in town.  [music]
You want to buy a little house, it's
€280,000 for a cabin in the middle of the
woods, or €
1,200,000,000, you get the giant house with a
panoramic view, for €4 million you
get an entire church with an
attached village.  This little town looks like
when Set McQueen gets stuck in the middle
of a town and this is exactly
Set McQueen's town and I'm
Set McQueen and I'm going to be stuck here
helping everyone do their jobs and then
Doc is going to make me faster than the
track.  In the end we went [music]
to a pub, also here with
live music, lots of old people,
we ate pizza, wings and
then we backed away and now I find myself
in the middle of the forest.  Franz took me
to the Redwood Armstrong Redwood
Natural Reserve,
which is a redwood forest
similar to Sequoia National Park, where I had
been with Franza years ago and we
are going to see a large
redwood.  This is the goal this
morning.  Let's start this trail.
After an hour and a half of climbing up
the mountain, among small trees that
honestly weren't sequoias, so I
wonder where the sequoias are, but
anyway we climbed, it was quite
tiring, we finally arrived here
at the panoramic point at the top of the
mountain.  There are other crossroads here.  Can you
continue the tour or can we
get off?  Maybe we will go down because in
reality the general seoglione is not here
but on the other side.  So let's go, so as
not to waste too much time, in the
direction of Secoglione, as we've been
around for a while now.
[music]
We went up the dirt road and
we go down the asphalt road.   Okay
.  Basically, all the likes we
just got were, so to speak,
useless because the sequoias weren't there,
but the sequoias are down here.  So down here
it's actually full of
redwoods.  There is also the Armstrong clone
which is, I think, the largest sequail in
this forest.  In fact, you can't
tell from the video, but it's very, very big and in
reality we could have
just taken this little walk among
the rocks on the plain.  It must be said that
Like is never thrown away because we
worked like two mules,
like two shears and this is good for our
health.
Stop and then start again.
Marcello, come on.  Why can't you see the
rocks?  Why?
[music]
But look, but look, you're missing out,
Marcello.  Look at this show.  You have to get
up, you have to look at the view.
[laughter] I'm having
a breakdown.
Oh, but they all taste the same.  But how many clips do
you want to make?
Oh, oh, all the same
on the beach the stone.  And chea on the stone by
car.
[music]
Goodnight Franz.  Good night,
Marcellino.
[music]